Clayton W. Seitz, PhD

cwseitz@iu.edu cwseitz.github.io

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I specialize in the development and application of machine learning methods for computer vision, time series analysis, and generative modeling. I maintain a strong background in functional and object-oriented programming with experience writing production quality software.

EDUCATION

Doctor of Philosopy, Physics Indiana University, Indianapolis, IN

2024

Master of Science, Physics

2021

University of Chicago, Chicago, IL

Bachelor of Science, Physics, Magna Cum Laude

2019

Indiana University, Bloomington, IN

Minor: Mathematics

Bachelor of Science, Informatics (Math Focus), Magna Cum Laude

2019

Indiana University, Bloomington, IN

EXPERIENCE

Graduate Researcher

2022-Present

Indiana University, Indianapolis, IN

- Designed diffusion models/score-based generative models and general computer vision techniques (object detection, segmentation, etc.) in PyTorch for modeling image datasets in super-resolution fluorescence microscopy
- Developed general probabilistic models for high-dimensional imaging datasets and associated Bayesian methods for statistical inference tasks
- Developed novel hardware systems for super-resolution imaging of human cells

Graduate Researcher

2020-2022

University of Chicago, Chicago, IL

- Investigated fundamental learning mechanisms in recurrent neural networks (RNNs) using dynamical models, mean-field theory, and time-series analysis.
- Designed and ran Monte Carlo simulations of spiking neural networks

Research Assistant

2019-2020

Indiana University, Indianapolis, IN

- Developed a scientific package in Python known as "cellquantifier" for highthroughput object detection and tracking
- Managed the package lifecycle and user training throughout the laboratory

Information Systems Intern

2016

Liberty Mutual Insurance

- Wrote Python scripts to automate attestation testing of web facing servers
- Assisted in configuration of web application firewalls (WAFs)

AWARDS

NIH Graduate Training Fellowship University of Chicago, Chicago, IL 2020

Travel Award and Lightning Talk Invitation Physical Sciences in Oncology - Minneapolis, MN 2019

Hudson and Holland Scholarship for Diversity and Inclusion

2013-2017

Indiana University, Bloomington, IN

Founders Scholar

2013-2017

Indiana University, Bloomington, IN

Cigital Scholarship

2016-2017

Indiana University, Bloomington, IN

PUBLICATIONS Clayton Seitz and Jing Liu. Quantum enhanced localization microscopy with a single photon avalanche diode array. In Review. 2024

> Clayton Seitz[†], Donghong Fu[†], Mengyuan Liu, Hailan Ma, and Jing Liu. BRD4 phosphorylation regulates the structure of chromatin nanodomains. In Review. 2024

> Clayton Seitz and Jing Liu. Uncertainty-aware localization microscopy by variational diffusion. In Review. 2024

> Maelle Locatelli[†], Josh Lawrimore[†], Hua Lin[†], Sarvath Sanaullah, Clayton Seitz, Dave Segall, Paul Kefer, Salvador Moreno Naike, Benton Lietz, Rebecca Anderson, Julia Holmes, Chongli Yuan, George Holzwarth, Bloom Kerry, Jing Liu, Keith D Bonin, Pierre-Alexandre Vidi. DNA damage reduces heterogeneity and coherence of chromatin motions. PNAS 12 July 2022; 119 (29): 1-11

> Mengdi Zhang, Clayton Seitz, Garrick Chang, Fadil Iqbal, Hua Lin, and Jing Liu A guide for single-particle chromatin tracking in live cell nuclei. Cell Biology International 15 January 2022; 46 (5): 683-700

> Wenting Wu, Farooq Syed, Edward Simpson, Chih-Chun Lee, Jing Liu, Garrick Chang, Chuanpeng Dong, Clayton Seitz, Decio L. Eizirik, Raghavendra G. Mirmira, Yunlong Liu, Carmella Evans-Molina; Impact of Proinflammatory Cytokines on Alternative Splicing Patterns in Human Islets. Diabetes 25 October 2021; 71 (1): 116 - 127

> Clayton Seitz, Hailan Ma, and Jing Liu. Cytokine-induced transcriptional memory is evident in the kinetics of transcriptional bursts. Biophysical Society Annual Conference 2022

> Clayton Seitz, Hua Lin, Keith Bonin, Pierre-Alexandre Vidi, and Jing Liu. Quantifying the spatiotemporal dynamics of dUTP labeled chromatin during the DNA damage response. Biophysical Society Annual Conference 2020

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages & Software: Linux, Bash, Python, R, PyTorch, C/C++, SQL, LaTeX, Git, Docker, SLURM